A Guide to the Peyton Family Papers 1746-1960
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Peyton Family Papers 1746-1960
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5843, 5843-b
This collection consists of ca. 50,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Peyton Family Papers were a gift to the Library on April 19, 1982 from Colonel John Peyton of "Peyton Hill," Manakin, Virginia and bear no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
The Peyton family collection consists of ca. 50,000 items (ca. 91 Hollinger boxes, ca. 52 linear shelf feet), 1746-1960, mainly correspondence, financial and legal papers, genealogical material, diaries, photographs, bound volumes, newspaper clippings, memorabilia, and other related miscellaneous material of the Peyton family of Stauton, Virginia. Other families represented in the collection include: Steele, Baldwin, Catlett, and Erskine. The papers pertain chiefly to social, business, and personal matters of various family members such as: Colonel John Lewis Peyton, L.W.H. Peyton, Margaret Erskine Catlett Peyton, Lawrence Washington Howe Peyton, and others.
Contents List
- Legal and Personal Papers 1746-1829 (Box 1)
- Primarily business, some personal [1839?] (Box 2)
- Personal and business papers 1840-1849 (Box 3)
- Business and personal papers 1840-1849 (Box 4)
- Primarily business, some personal [1853?] (Box 5)
- Business and personal papers 1850-1952 (Box 6)
- Business papers and personal correspondence, some printed 1856-1859 (Box 7)
- Personal and business correspondence 1859-1861 (Box 8)
- Primarily business, some personal 1862-1866 (Box 9)
- Primarily business papers, some personal correspondence, AMs notebook, some printed material 1848 (Box 10)
- Business and legal papers, checks and receipts, personal correspondence 1867-1868 (Box 11)
- Primarily business papers, receipts 1868-1869 (Box 12)
- Business and legal papers 1869-1870 (Box 13)
- Business and legal papers, personal correspondence 1870 (Box 14)
- Primarily business and legal papers, some personal correspondence and printed 1871 (Box 15)
- Business and legal papers [1871-1872?] (Box 16)
- Business and personal papers; receipts 1872 (Box 17)
- Primarily business papers, some personal correspondence and printed material 1872 (Box 18)
- Primarily receipts and business papers 1873-1874 (Box 19)
- Primarily business and legal papers, some personal correspondence, receipts 1873-1876 (Box 20)
- Primarily business papers, money receipts, some printed material 1868-1879 (Box 21)
- Primarily business correspondence, some personal 1878-1881 (Box 22)
- Business and personal correspondence, receipts 1880-1881 (Box 23)
- Receipts, business and legal and personal correspondence, some printed material 1882-1885 (Box 24)
- Business and legal papers, receipts 1882-1885 (Box 25)
- Printed material, receipts, personal and business papers 1886-1890 (Box 26)
- Business and personal correspondence, receipts, printed material 1891-1893 (Box 27)
- Primarily personal correspondence, receipts and cancelled checks, personal papers, some printed material 1894-1895 (Box 28)
- Primarily personal papers, receipts and checks; some printed 1896 (Box 29)
- Personal letters to Miss Margaret Catlett and Peyton's mother 1899-1903 (Box 30)
- Primarily personal correspondence of Miss Margaret Catlett 1899-1903 (Box 31)
- Personal correspondence w/Margaret Catlett- Personal, legal and business papers, much printed material 1904-1926 (Box 32)
- Personal, business, and military papers, receipts and bills 1932-1940, 1941-[1952?] (Box 33)
- Payne- Personal, Business papers and legal documents, many cancelled checks 1926-1945 (Box 34)
- M. Peyton- Special Account: cancelled checks only 1927 (Box 35)
- Karr, Kiger, Kent-Hamp: Business papers and legal documents 1925-1935 (Box 36)
- Hendren-Tremble, variable suits - business papers and legal documents, some printed material 1925-1941 (Box 37)
- Business papers and bills, some business correspondence 1927 (Box 38)
- Primarily bills and business papers, some personal correspondence 1927-1930 (Box 39)
- Mostly personal correspondence- primarily to Miss Betty Peyton 1931 (Box 40)
- Bldg.- Westwood- primarily business papers and legal documents; some printed material, cancelled checks 1926-1949 (Box 41)
- Mills-Williams Estate- business papers and legal documents 1932-1947 (Box 42)
- Notebooks: - diaries, school notes[?], bank book, etc. Business papers, bills and receipts, legal documents 1868-1885 (Box 43)
- Business papers and legal documents, receipts 1931-1944 (Box 44)
- Business papers and legal documents, printed material, reports 1931-1946 (Box 45)
- West Augusta Farm- Diary, chiefly sheet music; folders re mineral rights (manganese ore), some printed material 1939-1940 (Box 46)
- Chaney V. Stover-Lakeview Corp., business papers and legal documents 1926-1949 (Box 47)
- Photographs and Etchings- Kern Estate, primarily photos [cabinet cards and visiting cards], a few framed, 2 etchings; a half-filled scrapbook; folder containing business papers re Elizabeth Kerr [1871-1936?] (Box 48)
- Masincup- Stauton Military Academy Business correspondence and receipts 1924-1937 (Box 49)
- Frozen Foods- Miscellaneous correspondence, business correspondence, estimates, receipts, forms, deeds 1932-1946 (Box 50)
- Checkbook w/ receipts, $500 bonds, scrapbook, cancelled checks, primarily business correspondence 1906-1937 (Box 51)
- Correspondence, chiefly business and receipts 1897-1898 (Box 52)
- Maps, dressmaking patterns, pamphlets (on maps), books, bound volumes and miscellaneous printed material [?] (Box 53)
- Correspondence- business and personal files on bank figures 1901-1931 (Box 54)
- Staunton Military Academy- Hendren mostly business correspondence, some printed material 1940-1946 (Box 55)
- Bank of Riverheads- primarily business correspondence, 1 folder of Society of Cincinnatti 1931-1944 (Box 56)
- Stover Trust- Lewis Mem. primarily legal correspondence, some printed material 1920-1949 (Box 57)
- West Augustan Farm Diary, Diary Vol. V. Nov. 6 1886-Nov. 5 1890, 1 folder w/loose receipts and business correspondence 1942-1949 (Box 58)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence: Social Security Act- UVA Alumni Association business correspondence-- primarily concerning VMI 1937-1949 (Box 59)
- L.W.H.P. Autobiog. - Berry P. Suit 16 chapters n.d. (Box 60)
- V.M.I. Board of Visitors- loose newspapers 1922 and 1896, 1944 business correspondence re VMI 1944 (Box 61)
- Porter- Zadarozny- legal papers and correspondence 1933-1946 (Box 62)
- Miscellaneous correspondence-- Office Building-- Barrister's Row---legal documents and correspondence, business correspondence, checks n.d. (Box 63)
- Society of the Cincinnatti- Chaney V. Stover speeches, legal documents and correspondence, loose papers re case synopses 1938-1948 (Box 64)
- Bank of Riverheads-- business/financial correspondence re various banks and businesses, legal documents 1931-1939 (Box 65)
- Newspapers, legal and financial papers, business correspondence [?] (Box 66)
- Hendren-Trimble business correspondence, some personal correspondence, legal documents, some financial papers, including cancelled checks 1930s and 1940s (Box 67)
- Blank checks, personal correspondence, notes, memos, business correspondence n.d. (Box 68)
- Personal correspondence, notes, poetry, sketches, printed material, some business correspondence n.d. (Box 69)
- Personal correspondence, newspaper clippings, notes, stories, some business correspondence n.d. (Box 70)
- Personal and business correspondence and some miscellaneous material n.d. (Box 71)
- Personal correspondence, school papers, stenographers' notebooks, practice typing and shorthand pages, some printed material n.d. (Box 72)
- Miss Margaret Catlett- personal correspondence 1900-1902 (Box 73)
- Federal and State tax records of L.W.H.P. and one folder of personal and business correspondence 1933-1947 (Box 74)
- Miscellaneous correspondence- Stuyvesant School business and personal correspondence, some printed material 1910-1947 (Box 75)
- [Moon Addition?] Corp. - business, legal, and personal papers and correspondence [?] (Box 76)
- Newspaper clippings ca. 1890- ca. 1920 (Box 77)
- Correspondence re VMI 1944-1946 (Box 78)
- John L. Peyton-Kilber v. Chaney business papers, legal documents and personal correspondence 1927-1949 (Box 79)
- Outerbridge-Middlebrook Ave. Bridge speeches, legal documents, personal correspondence, and business papers 1927-1947 (Box 80)
- Business Correspondence, papers-deeds, contracts 1913-1949 (Box 81)
- Business papers - legal matters 1930-1942 (Box 82)
- Business papers - legal matters 1930-1937 (Box 83)
- Business papers, correspondence 1924-1947 (Box 84)
- Business papers, correspondence - legal matters 1927-1942 (Box 85)
- Business papers, correspondence 1931-1942 (Box 86)
- Business papers, correspondence 1930-1940 (Box 87)
- Business papers, correspondence, legal matters 1937-1948 (Box 88)
- Notebooks, journals, printed material 1884-1894 (Box 89)
- Business correspondence, papers 1930-1946 (Box 90)
- Journals, ledger 1884-1948 (Box 91)
- Journal, photo, personal correspondence, genealogy research on Erskine family 1839-1946 (Box 92)
- Personal correspondence, notes, newspaper cuttings, printed material, photo, papers [ca. 1900-?] (Box 93)
- Newspaper cuttings, notes, personal correspondence, photos ca. 1860-ca. 1920 (Box 94)
- Magazine, notes and correspondence re genealogy research ca. 1900-1930 (Box 95)
- Scrapbook, photos, notes and papers re genealogy research, newspaper clippings, printed material 1800-1900 (Box 96)
- Magazines about history and genealogy, notebook of genealogy research 1857-1858 (Box 97)
- Printed materials, personal correspondence, correspondence re genealogy research ca. 1900-1950 (Box 98)